YUHONG LIU

Unit 912 - 70 Forest Manor Rd ● North York, ON, Canada, M2J 0A9 ● Phone: (647) 669-8839 ● liuyuhongsh@gmail.com

PROFILE

KEY SKILLS

Dedicated analytics professional with more than 4 years of experiences in designing data visualizations and applying business intelligence technologies for enterprise reporting and analysis

Teradata, MS SQL, Oracle SAS EG, R, MATLAB MicroStrategy, Tableau

Excel Macro VBA Pyspark, Pandas, Numpy Python, Java OOP Lean Six Sigma, DMAIC Financial Mathematics Spark, Hive SQL

Linux Command Line HTML, CSS, Web design OR model & algorithm

EDUCATION

 $2014 \sim 2016$ $2009 \sim 2014$ $2007 \sim 2011$

Master of Engineering - Industrial Engineering Bachelor of Applied Science - Industrial Engineering Dean's Honor List - Fall & Winter 2014 Honor Bachelor of Science - Actuarial Science and Statistics

University of Toronto University of Toronto

University of Toronto

EXPERIENCE

Bell Canada (Small Business F2F/Dealer Channel Sales Team)

Specialist, Marketing Intelligence & Sales Analytics - F2F/Dealer Channel

Developer, Business Intelligence - Subscriber & Performance Analytics

January 2016 - Present

June 2014 – September 2015

- Managed Bell SMB marketing intelligence programs for over 70 agents and resulted 100% growth in sales
- Conducted commission calculation and incentive analysis for multiple vendors in ON and QC
- Managed the CRM tool development with cross-functional collaboration of Marketing, BI and IT
- Generated sales leads using wireless subscriber base and designed effective cross-sell strategies
- Conducted strategic capacity planning and region segmentation for F2F channel teams in ON & QC
- Created various ad-hoc reports and analysis on Sales, Marketing Intelligence and Agent Performance

Bell Mobility

(Rational AM-

Team)

EADC core PMO

(Customer Operations and Marketing Insight Team)

Accomplished a full leadership rotation in Bell's IPTV technical support centre and retail stores

- Conducted IVR process improvement project with estimated saving of \$58K per year
- Coordinated \$250K+budget EDW data integration project with multiple stakeholders across organization
- Provided trainings in MicroStrategy visual insight for 200+ internal clients including multiple VP's
- Piloted and created the first mobile business intelligence dashboard across Bell Mobility
- Generated ad-hoc SQL & SAS reports for senior executives in Sales, Marketing and Customer Operations
- Automated data querying using self-served MicroStrategy dashboards and SAS EG

Intern, Release Operation and Project Management **IBM Canada**

May 2012 - April 2014

- Facilitated more than 43 software releases and legal clearances of IBM Rational AM products
- Participated in defect projection and established goals for 37 products owned by 2 division VP's
- Conducted weekly APAR (defect) & RFE (require for enhancement) tracking and reporting
- Designed and automated the RFE reporting process using Java, Perl, and Linux email server
- Acted as a focal point for Rational AM products under IBM Clearing House Initiative and
- Reduced total of more than 200 data integrity issues within 3 month period
- Hosted multiple IBM software release legal training sessions for team members

TRAINING & CERTIFICATE

Green Belt Certificate in Lean Manufacturing and Six Sigma November 2013 Deloitte accelerated Business course in Project, Change and Risk management October 2010 SAS Programming I & II, Statistical Analysis I, Intro to Macro September 2014 MicroStrategy - Advanced Reporting, Project Design Essential, Advance Project Design October 2014 SOA/CAS/CIA Exam of Actuarial Probability March 2009 SOA/CAS/CIA Exam Financial Mathematics for Actuaries August 2009

PROJECTS & THESIS M.Eng Project - 211Toronto.ca Web Session Analysis and Visualization

An end to end web session analysis of 211Toronto.ca's web log including raw data ETL, sessionization of visits, and data visualization using Apache Spark, Jupyter notebook and Tableau

Thesis - Study of inventory and pricing management policy for stochastic and seasonal demand

Analyzed existing inventory optimization models, pricing strategies, as well as dynamitic programming algorithms for potential application in estimating goods with seasonal demand

Thesis - Application of SLA & MIP optimal inventory rebalancing route for Bike Sharing

Proposed a bike station inventory rebalancing model based on service level requirement bounds, mixed integer programming and travelling salesmen problem model with sample case studies

PUBLICATION

Integrated Solution for Timely Delivery of Customer Change Requests Vehicle routing optimization by multiple-dynamic saving algorithm

IJUNESST Vol. 7, No. 2 JIEM Vol. 7, No. 2

LANGUAGES

English (fluent), Mandarin (mother tongue), Cantonese (listening)

Able to Relocate & Travel Extensively • Available for Full-Time & Contract Assignments